Now let's take a look at the key stakeholders in a freelancing ecosystem.
لننظر الآن إلى صاحب المصلحة الرئيسي في نظام العمل الحر.
Let's start with you, the freelancer,
ولنبدأ بك، الموظف الحر الذي يملك مهارات
who has a skill that can be used for clients' projects and ready to take on work.
يمكنه استخدامها في مشاريع العملاء ومستعد لتلقي طلبات العمل.
The other is the client who is looking to get a specific task done through a freelancer.
أما الشخص الآخر فهو العميل الذي يريد إنجاز مهمة محددة من خلال موظف حر.
Now, a client could either be an individual or a company.
ويمكن للعميل أن يكون فردًا أو شركة.
It is also common for large companies to hire freelancers to get short-term tasks done.
من الشائع أيضًا أن توظف الشركات الكبيرة العمالة الحرة لإنجاز المهام قصيرة الأمد.
Many times, there is also an intermediary involved,
في كثير من الأحيان يكون هناك وسيطًا أيضًا
which connects the client and the freelancer,
يربط العملاء بالموظفين
helps them find each other,
ويساعدهم على إيجاد بعضهم البعض،
and in some cases also manage payments, etc.
وفي بعض الحالات أيضًا يكون هو من يتولى أمور الدفع وما إلى ذلك.
Now, examples of these intermediaries would be
الأمثلة على تلك الجهات الوسيطة هي
freelancing platforms that we will cover in detail in this course,
منصات العمل الحر التي سوف نتناولها بالتفصل في هذه الدورة التدريبية
or job sites, which not only advertise
أو مواقع العمل والتي لا يتوقف دورها على الإعلان
full-time jobs but also short-term freelancing positions.
عن وظائف الدوام الكامل ولكن أيضًا عن الأعمال الحرة قصيرة الأمد.